<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="AFARS_AFARS_topic_699" xml:lang="en-US"><title outputclass="Heading 3"><ph props="autonumber">5137.7204-92</ph> Ordering procedures.</title><conbody><p outputclass="List1">(a)  The contracting officer shall issue a separate order for each required training session (e.g. year, semester, term, or quarter), and obligate funds to cover the instruction of those individuals identified on the order form for the period specified.</p><p outputclass="List1">(b)  The contracting officer may issue an order for the next fiscal year prior to the availability of funds, notwithstanding 5132.7 to preclude delays in enrollment.  Insert the clause in FAR 52.232-18, Availability of Funds, in the order.  When the funds become available, the contracting officer shall use Standard Form 30 to modify the order to cite the appropriation chargeable and to delete the Availability of Funds clause.</p><p outputclass="List1">(c)  An order may authorize the enrollment of any number of military personnel or Reserve Officers’ Training Corps (ROTC) scholarship cadets and must –</p><p outputclass="List2">(1)  Identify each individual authorized to enroll by name and rank; for ROTC scholarship cadets, show social security number in lieu of rank;</p><p outputclass="List2">(2)  Identify the individual as an Army Medical Department member or ROTC scholarship cadet, when applicable;</p><p outputclass="List2">(3)  Identify each course for which the individual is enrolling and its actual or estimated cost;</p><p outputclass="List2">(4)  State the appropriation chargeable for the instruction of each individual; and</p><p outputclass="List2">(5)  Include the statement:  “Whenever the actual cost of a course will exceed the estimated cost shown on this order by $100 or more, the Contractor shall submit a written request for approval to the Contracting Officer prior to commencing instruction.”</p></conbody></concept>